portfolio.kaylalynjones.ninja

2011 Riverside Drive, Nashville, TN 37216

"I love to create beautiful digital experiences that merge functionality and design. With my varied background in both Fine Arts and Client Services, I provide a fresh perspective that is pivotal to great, user-friendly software."

## **Skills**

User Interface Design Responsive Web Design
User Experience Test Driven Development

# **Professional Experience**

Nashville Software School July 2014-Jan 2015

An intensive, full-time six month bootcamp for software engineering and web development. Developed full stack web and mobile apps in an iterative and faced-paced environment. Utilized techniques such as pair programming and test-driven development. Collaborated with peers to solve problems and design effective and efficient solutions.

Freelance Designer

July 2013 - July 2014

Developed custom web sites, created graphics, illustrated flowcharts, constructed sitemaps and personas for user experience models.

Shop Manager

Feb 2012 - July 2013

Alterations by Blair

Developed and implemented a customized system for scheduling tasks, increasing efficiency and reliability.

## Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts

May 2013

Delta State University

Magna Cum Laude

Fields of study: painting, color theory, printmaking, fiber art.

# Technology

Javascript MongoDB Html/Jade PostgreSQL

CSS/CSS3 Git
SASS/LESS Grunt
jQuery Gulp
AngularJS Bower
Express/Hapi AWS
Node.js Heroku

Socket.IO Adobe Photoshop Mocha/Chai Adobe Illustrator

Cordova Ionic

# **Projects**

#### NashVesTN

Finalist at HackNashville6

Group Project: Project Manager, UI & Mobile Dev

Utilizing the MEAN Stack, Ionic, and Cordova we created Mobile & Desktop apps that help non-profit organizations increase their community impact by engaging the Millennial Generation.

### Abode

# Mid-term Capstone for NSS UI/UX, Frontend & Backend

For the mid-session Capstone project at NSS, I used the MEAN Stack, Twitter API and Socket.IO to create an application for ambitious homeowners to manage their renovation goals and inspirations.

## **EnlighTN**

## Group Project: UI/UX & Frontend

Using publicly available data on the installation and performance art in Nashville from various sources such as nashville.data.gov. We utilized the MEAN Stack, Twitter API, Socket.IO, and Geolocation to offer a comprehensive one stop view for all Metro Art and Historical Markers.